史上最逊的文艺复兴集会
Worst. renaissance. fair. ever.
别再墨迹了  谢尔顿
Please let it go, sheldon.
还原历史的准确度也太低了
It was rife with historical inaccuracies.
举个例子  客栈的女服务生上给我们一大壶蜂蜜酒
For example, the tavern girl serving flagons of mead.
她的服装明显是日耳曼式的
Her costume was obviously germanic.
但在1487年  巴伐利亚纯酿法令
But in 1487, the bavarian purity laws,
或者叫"纯度法令"
Or "reinheitsgebot,"
严格限制了蜂蜜酒的可用性
Severely limited the availability of mead.
最多他们只能用一点调味酒
At best, they would have had some sort of spiced wine.
你真是太吹毛求疵了
You're nitpicking.
是吗
Oh, really?
那我就再来挑一下疵  那个酒壶
Well here is another nit for you.The flagons
在以前绝对不会是用聚丙烯做的
Would not have been made of polypropylene.
文艺复兴集会的重点不是历史准确度有多高
Renaissance fairs aren't about historical accuracy.
重点在于把那些在金考公司上班的丰满女孩们带来
They're about taking chubby girls who work at kinko's
给她们系上紧身胸衣
And lacing them up in corsets so tight
好让她们的波波跳出来和我们说  您好
Their bosom jumps out and says, "howdy."
十五世纪的胸部不会说  您好
Bosoms would not have said "howdy" in the 15th century.
如果要说的话  也只能是  万岁
If anything, they would've said, "huzzah."
我才不管波波说什么  谢尔顿
I don't care what the bosoms say, sheldon.
只要它们在对我说话就好
I just want to be part of the conversation.
伙计们
Hi, guys.
好像你们刚才去文艺复兴集会了
Looks like you've been to the renaissance fair...
我希望是
I'm hoping.
文艺复兴集会吗
Renaissance fair?
更像是中世纪兼启蒙时代
More of a medieval, slash, age of enlightenment,
兼找借口穿遮阴布的集会
Slash, any-excuse- to-wear-a-codpiece fair.
好吧  随便你
Okay, fine, whatever.
伙计们  这是我的朋友  埃里克
You guys, this is my friend eric.
很高兴见到你
So, yeah, good to see you.
我也是
It's good to see you, too.
我们应该走了
We should probably go.
大家再见
Bye, guys.
我很喜欢你的帽子
I like your hat.
谢谢  是我妈做的
Thanks, my mom made it.
佩妮有了新男友  非常尴尬
Penny with a new guy, tres awkward.
没什么尴尬的
It wasn't awkward.
不过也不算好玩
It wasn't fun.
再说了  有什么关系
Besides, what's the big deal?
我们约会过  然后不约会了  事情已经过去了
We dated, we stopped dating, and now we're both moving on.
你说过去了的意思
By moving on,
是不是指当她和另外一个男人约会的时候
Do you mean she's going out with other men
你却整个下午都在
And you spent the afternoon
和沃罗威茨做十五世纪的肥皂
Making 15th-century soap with wolowitz?
那不是十五世纪的肥皂
That was not 15th century soap.
我的天呐  那些人必须得学学
My god, those people need to learn
不是在一样东西名字前加上"老"字[仿古字]
You can't just put "ye olde" in front of anything you want
就能冒充古老的东西了
And expect to get away with it.
我们快点进去好吗
Can we please just go in?
我的锁子甲被夹在内裤里了
My chain mail's stuck in my underwear.
你穿了现代的内裤
You're wearing modern underwear?
相对来说是现代的
Relatively modern.
干嘛  你穿了什么
Why, what are you wearing?
我严格遵守历史  准确无误地
I fashioned historically accurate undergarments
穿着亚麻布内衣
Out of linen.
你去买亚麻布了
You went out and bought linen?
别傻了  我只是借用了你的枕头套
Don't be silly-- I borrowed one of your pillowcases.
借用
Borrowed?
你们知道吗  我很高兴佩妮有了新发展
You know what,I'm happy that Penny's moving on.
这样我就可以自由前进了
It gives me the freedom to move on myself.
你的意思是你一直以来都在踌躇
Are you saying that you've been holding back?
当然
Of course.
出于对她的尊敬
Out of respect.
那么在佩妮之前的十年你怎么解释
So, how do you explain the ten years before penny?
那时候你在尊敬谁
Who were you respecting then?
我和很多女人约会过啊
Well, I've dated plenty of women.
有乔伊斯·金
There was joyce kim...
莱斯利·温克尔
Leslie winkle...
通知一下牛津词典的编者
Notify the editors of the oxford english dictionary.
"许多"这个词被重新定义为"二个"
The word "plenty" has been redefined to mean "two."
去年那个在动漫展里的那个女孩呢
What about that girl last year at comic-con?
不算
Doesn't count.
为什么
Why not?
在动漫展服装扮演里发生的事情
What happens in costume at comic-con
只是动漫展的事情
Stays at comic-con.
你这样说
You're only saying that
只是因为你的那件事
Because of what happened to you.
什么事
What happened to you?
没什么
Nothing happened to me.
这不是你的错  拉吉
It wasn't your fault, raj.
他只是打扮成了绿色的猎户座女奴
He was dressed as a green orion slave girl.
怎么开始说我了
How did we get on me?!
我们不是在嘲笑莱纳德吗
We were mocking leonard for not moving on.
老兄  你完全是在原地踏步啊
Dude, you have totally not moved on.
不是这样的
Yes, I have.
现在我只需要
It's just a matter of actually making
-和别人出去约会而已  -谁
A date with someone. like who?
乔伊斯·金
Well... there's joyce kim.
但她已经叛逃回朝鲜了
But she defected back to north korea,
所以在地理上来说有点小困难
So that's a little geographically undesirable.
那莱斯利·温克尔呢
What about leslie winkle?
-不行  -为什么
Oh, no. why?
她的研究方法论漏洞百出
Her research methodology is sloppy,
她在说圈量子引力论的时候毫无道理的傲慢自大
She's unjustifiably arrogant about loop quantum gravity,
而且更糟的是  她对我很坏
And to make matters worse, she's often mean to me.
我觉得她很火辣
I think she's smoking hot.
同意
I'd hit that.
你觉得胶体悬浮系统上的
You'd hit particulate soil
微粒污垢也很火辣
In a colloidal suspension.
泥巴
Mud.
我喜欢莱斯利  但她对约会并不感兴趣
Look, I like leslie, but she's not interested
她只想使用男人的工具来缓解自己的压力
In dating as much as using men as tools for stress release.
那又如何  做她的工具好了
Yeah, so? be a tool.
你也可以给自己缓解一下"压力"
Go get yourself a little rebound "stress release."
严格来说  要是他和佩妮有过亲密接触的话
Technically, it would only be rebound if he and penny
那才能算是缓解压力
Had actually engaged in physical intimacy.
你是说像你和女奴理查德[男子名]那样吗
You mean like you and richard the slave girl?
我给他买了晚饭  然后亲了一下
I bought him dinner and we kissed once!
就结束了
That was it.
而且他告诉我他叫金伯利
And he told me his name was kimberly.
你知道我们如何知道我们不是在母体里的么[骇客帝国]
You know how I know we're not in the matrix?
如何
How?
如果我们是的话  这些食物就不会这么糟了
If we were, the food would be better.
嗨  莱纳德
Hey, Leonard.
嗨  莱斯利
Hey, Leslie.
嗨  傻蛋
Hey, dummy.
你好
Hello, to you...
你这个智商不够的人
Insufficiently intelligent person.
快把我送到烧伤病房[阿甘正传里台词]
Ooh, rush me to the burn unit.
莱纳德  你有空么
Hey, Leonard, do you have a second?
-我想问你几个问题 -当然
-I need to ask you something. -sure.
如果你不介意的话
Well, if you'll excuse me,
我要去做一些成绩斐然的工作
I'm going to go do work that promises
而不像你做的
Significant results, as opposed to what you do...
那些没有意义的
Which does not.
没错  就是说你呢
Yeah, you heard me.
我听说你和佩妮吹了
So, I heard your relationship with Penny crashed to the ground
就像从飞机厕所里扔出的蓝冰一样吹了
Like blue ice falling out of an airplane lavatory.
这你是听谁说的
Where did you hear that?
其实是我读到的  沃罗威茨发短信给我
Actually, I read it. Wolowitz texted me.
"就像从飞机厕所里扔出的蓝冰一样"  好吧
"like blue ice falling out of an airplane lavatory," yeah.
我觉得这个笑话很不错  我发给他一个LOL[笑脸]
I thought it was a pretty good one. I gave him an lol.
不过  这让我想到
Anyway, it got me thinking.
你现在是单身一人
Now that you're unattached,
说不定我们能重温一下之前的关系
Maybe we can revisit our previous attachment.
你是在暗示再来一次"舒缓压力"么
Are you suggesting another bout of stress release?
不  我受够临时性爱了
No, I'm all done with casual sex.
从现在开始
From now on, I'm fully committed
我只要传统的关系模式
To the traditional relationship paradigm.
真的  这之间有什么不同
Really? what changed?
很难说
It's hard to say.
我想大概在每个女人一生总有那么一段时间
I guess there's just a time in every woman's life
厌倦了醒来发现自己躺在陌生的沙发上
When she gets tired of waking up on a strange futon
和一群她根本不认识的人在一起
With a bunch of people she doesn't know.
我明白  一群人
Yeah, I can see how that would-- a bunch of people?
无论如何  我想该是慢慢来的时候了
Anyway, I figure it's time to slow things down
又有谁比你更适合慢慢来呢
And who better to slow things down with than you?
噢  我深感荣幸
Oh... I'm flattered.
那你认为我们应该怎么开始
So how do you suggest we proceed?
去你家  点份中国菜  租一部电影
Your place, we'll order chinese, you'll rent a movie--
文艺一点但不要那么深奥  然后轻轻的抚摸  不发生性关系
Artsy, but accessible-- then light petting, no coitus.
听起来不错
Sounds fun.
你可以来决定那些细节部分
I'll leave the details up to you.
我想如果你设想你是男性角色的话会比较好
I think it's better if you assume the male role.
谢谢  想的真周到
Thank you, that's very thoughtful.
好
Great.
给我电话
Call me.
好消息
Great news.
我妈把我的N64游戏机[任天堂的]寄来了
My mom sent me my old nintendo 64.
-不错嘛  -你知道这意味着什么吗
-Terrific -you know what this means, don't you?
把红牛那关打通之后
Break out the red bull,
马里奥差不多就能通关了  怀念旧日校园生活啊
It's time to rock mario, old school.
今天晚上貌似我有别的计划了
I kind of have other plans tonight.
可今天是星期五啊
But it's friday.
星期五一直都是怀旧电玩之夜呀
Friday's always vintage game night.
你看我妈把记忆卡也寄来了
Look, mom included the memory card.
我们可以从我1999年的纪录接着打
We can pick up right where I left off in 1999
那时候我得了恶性贫血症
When I had pernicious anemia.
问题是有人要来
Well, the thing is, someone's coming over.
没关系  我有三副手柄
Okay, no problem. I have three controllers.
人多齐欢乐
The more the merrier.
谢尔顿  是个约会
Sheldon, it's a date.
我有个约会
I have a date coming over.
不要怪我猜不到是这么回事
Well, you can't blame me for not jumping to that conclusion.
为什么  我有约会这事很新奇么
Why? what's so unusual about me having a date?
统计学意义上  是的
Well, statistically speaking...
好吧
All right, all right.
不管怎么说  我有个约会
Well, nevertheles, I have one now
如果你能呈缺省态
And I'd appreciate it if you would, you know,
我会感激不尽的
Make yourself scarce.
莱纳德  我是理论物理学家
Leonard, I'm a published theoretical physicist
我有两个博士学位
With two doctorates and an iq
还有普通测试无法准确测量的智商水平
Which can't be accurely measured by normal tests.
我还能更稀缺点么
How much scarcer could I be?
你知道我的意思的
You know what I mean.
你能不能给我们一点私人空间
Could you just give us a little privacy?
-你想让我离开这个公寓  -是的
-You want me to leave the apartment? -yes.
你是说让我去别的什么地方
You mean, just go someplace else and be...
待在别的什么地方么
Someplace else?
是的
Yes.
为什么要我走  这也是我的公寓啊
Well, why should I leave? this is my apartment, too.
我知道  如果科学家能够发现你们种族里
I know it is, and if science ever discovers a second member
你的另一个同类  如果你们两个想要一点隐私
Of your species and you two would like some privacy,
我绝对乐意不碍你的事
I'd be more than happy to get out of your way.
那好吧
Well, all right then.
谢尔顿  你在这干嘛呢
Sheldon, what are you doing?
在用糟糕代码写的N64模拟器
Playing super mario on a poorly coded
玩超级马里奥
Nintendo 64 emulator.
但你干嘛坐在楼梯上玩
Yeah, but why are you doing it on the stairs?
我就是当代拿破仑
I am a modern day napoleon
被驱逐到楼梯间的厄尔巴岛
Exiled to the elba of the staircase
因为莱纳德告诉我他要约会
Because Leonard, get this, has a date.
他动作真快嘛
Oh. oh, well, good for him.
但你为什么要坐这玩呢
Yeah, but why are you sitting here?
你为什么不去看场电影  玩点别的
Why don't you just go to a movie or something?
自己去
Alone?
对啊  怎么了
Yeah, why not?
如果我被爆米花噎住了
What if I choke on my popcorn?
谁对我实施哈姆立克急救法
Who will administer the heimlich maneuver?
别买爆米花不就行了
Well, then don't order popcorn.
看电影不吃爆米花  听听你自己说的
No popcorn at the mov... listen to yourself.
你为什么不去咖啡店呢
Why don't you go to a coffee shop?
我不喝咖啡
I don't drink coffee.
还有别的可以点啊
They have other things.
有什么呢
What do they have?
很多啊  饼干啊 油酥点心啊
I don't know. you know, cookies, pastries...
-那种熊掌形状的油酥点心么  -对啊
-Pastries such as bear claws? -Yeah, sure.
我不喜欢熊掌
I don't like bear claws.
嗨  佩妮
Hey, penny.
傻蛋
Dumbass.
莱斯利·温克尔
Leslie winkle.
全世界这么多实验室里
Of all the overrated physicists
这么多被高估的物理学家
In all the labs in all the world,
为什么偏偏就选中了莱斯利·温克尔
Why does it have to be leslie winkle?
因为他们有很多共同点啊
Well, they have a lot in common.
我是说  他们都是科学家
I mean, they're both scientists.
求你了  如果他们要重新把猩猩送上太空
Oh, please. the only way she could make
那就是她对科学
A contribution to science would be
唯一的贡献
If they resumed sending chimps into space.
好吧  我也有个约会
Okay, well, I have a date, too,
那就待会见
So I'll see ya.
大家都有约会
Everybody has a date.
就连你  马里奥  也在追碧奇公主
Even you, mario, going after princess peach.
那我在干嘛
And what am I doing?
我只是在使唤你
I'm just enabling you.
蛮鲜美的鸡肉
It's pretty good chiken
对啊  是陈记的
Yeah, it's from chang's.
-不是周记的  -不是  是陈记的
Not chow's? no, chang's.
周记出什么问题了
What happened to chow's?
变了
It changed.
你觉得我们应该要几个孩子
So, how many children do you think we should have?
抱歉  这个有点唐突了
I'm sorry. that was a little abrupt.
只是有点
A little?
我是说  我们有那么多事情可以说
I mean, there are so many things to talk about
干嘛要讨论繁殖问题
Before we discuss reproduction.
我也希望是
I sure hope so.
除了短小
Besides shortness,
你们家族还有什么基因缺陷
What genetic weaknesses run in your family?
抱歉打扰了
Sorry to interrupt.
电池要没电了  你们继续
Battery's dying. continue.
基因缺陷  对
Uh, genetic weakness, right.
有一个乳糖不耐症
Uh, there's the lactose intolerance.
别忘了说男性秃头
Don't forget the male-pattern baldness.
他的叔叔们坐在餐桌旁的时候
When his uncles sit around the dinner table,
看起来就像半盒鸡蛋摆在那
They look like a half carton of eggs.
好吧  我的叔叔们都是秃头  不过我的婶婶艾德娜
Okay, yeah, my uncles are bald, but my aunt edna
是你将遇见的头发最多的女人之一  所以
Is one of the hairiest women you'll ever meet, so...
漂亮女人
Sweet lady.
每次她抱我的时候都挠我痒痒
Always tickles when she hugs me.
又怎么了
What now?
我要撒尿尿
I have to make pee-pee.
我很抱歉谢尔顿的打扰
Listen, I'm sorry about all of sheldon's interruptions.
他总是有点怪怪的
He can be a bit of an eccentric.
如果"怪怪的"是指消极攻击人格[看似支持  其实捣乱]
If by "eccentric" you mean passive-aggressive
东德州的风孔  那我倒同意
East texas blowhole, I agree.
我想今晚是一个很好的开始
I think tonight was a very good start.
我也觉得
Me, too.
你确定你可以推迟交往
Are you sure you're okay postponing intercourse
直到我们的关系度过了最初的可行性测试吗
Until our relationship is past the initial viability test?
没问题
No, problem.
我非常擅长于推迟交往
I'm very skilled at postponing intercourse.
我想我可以打电话给你
I guess I'll call you
然后我们再安排另外一个约会
And we'll arrange another evening.
可以  我相信协议指出了你至少
Yes, I believe protocol dictates that you wait a minimum
要等18个小时才能打电话给我
Of 18 hours before you call
这样我才不会厌恶你的猴急
So I'm not repulsed by your cloying eagerness.
可以
Sure.
再说一次  你自己决定  你是男人
Again, it's your decision. you're the man.
不是我的猫
It wasn't my cat.
是一个试验
It was an experiment
一个薛定谔的人设计的
Designed by this guy named schroedinger.
是查理·布朗动画片里面的[史努比动画片]
From the charlie brown cartoons?
不是  他是个科学家
No, he was some kind of scientist.
我重新说一遍
Let me start again.
嘿  莱纳德
Oh, hey, leonard.
你好
Hello.
莱斯利
Leslie.
你好
Hi.
好吧  晚安
Okay, well, good night.
还不够劲
That ain't gonna make your point.
够了
That's enough.
给我电话
Call me.
好的
Right.
好的  晚安
Okay, good night.
什么
Uh, what?
今天不错  再见
Had a great time. ciao.
抱歉  我不会再去那个文艺复兴集会了
I'm sorry, I am not going back to the renaissance fair.
拜托  谢尔顿
Come on, sheldon.
没有多少地方我可以穿杰斯特的服装[小丑]
There's so few places I can wear my jester costume.
我才不管  那里太多历史怪人了
I don't care. there are far too many historical anomalies
不对我的胃口
For my comfort.
好吧  你看这个如何
Okay, how about this?
你可以穿装扮成星际迷航的科学官
You can go dressed as a star trek science officer
探索一个类似十六世纪地球的星球
Exploring a planet similar to earth in the 1500s.
你是说像斯坡克那样[企业号上的科学官]
You mean, like spock?
对的
Sure.
太棒了
Fascinating.
嘿  科学家小伙们
Hey, fellow scientists...
谢尔顿
Sheldon.
我们干嘛不移到那边去  这样莱斯利就可以坐在一起了
Why don't we all move over there so leslie can join us?
好的  去吧
Yeah, let's do it.
如果你很难决定去做哪边
If you're having trouble deciding where to sit,
我可以建议看一下是一个土豆  两个土豆[影片名]
May I suggest one potato, two potato?
或者我叫它 "莱斯利·温克尔的实验性方法论"
Or as I call it, "the leslie winkle experimental methodology."
别让我难做啊
Don't make this hard for me.
一点也不难
It's not hard.
非常简单  你要么跟我
It's simple. you can either sit with me,
你的朋友  同事还有室友一起坐
Your friend, colleague and roommate
要么跟一个你们可能一起睡过的
Or you can sit with an overrated scientist
高估的科学家一起坐
You might have sex with.
你说对了  非常简单
You're right, it is simple.
嘿  谢尔顿
Hey, sheldon.
佩妮
Penny.
今晚跑三楼了  弄不清了
Third floor tonight-- mixing it up?
我还是不明白为什么
I still don't understand why
你不去吃饭或是什么
You don't just go to dinner or something.
好吧
All right,
那我们就说我独自去吃饭
Let's say I go to dinner alone,
我吃饭的时候  如果我要去上厕所
And during the meal, I have to use the restroom.
我怎么知道有没有人碰了我的食物
How do I know someone's not touching my food?
晚安  谢尔顿
Good night, sheldon.
佩妮  等一下
Penny, hold on.
你确定你和莱纳德没戏了
Are you sure things can't work out with you and leonard?
你说什么
Excuse me?
我只是在想 如果你能试试旧学院派的做法
I'm just wondering if you really gave it the old college try.
或者就你而言  旧社区大学的做法
Or in your case, the old community college try.
好了  这从何说起
Okay, where is this coming from?
莱纳德此刻正在楼上和我的死敌在一起
Leonard is upstairs right now with my archenemy.
你的死敌
Your archenemy?
是的  就如毁灭博士对神奇侠
Yes, the dr. doom to my mr. fantastic.
章鱼博士对蜘蛛侠
Dr. octopus to my spider-man,
西瓦那博士对超人上尉
The dr. sivana to my captain marvel.
我明白了  明白了  明白了
I get it, I get it, I get it.
那你知道  这么多超人都有
Do you know, it's amazing how many supervillains
高学位有多棒吗
Have advanced degrees.
学校毕业后可以找个比大多数人
Graduate school should probably do a better job
做得都好的工作
Of screening those people out.
谢尔顿  打住  你把我绕晕了
Sheldon, come back. you're losing me.
我的死敌是莱斯利·温克尔  佩妮
It's leslie winkle, penny.
她看不起我的研究
She belittles my research.
亲爱的  太遗憾了
Oh, sweetie, I'm sorry.
她叫我"傻蛋"
She called me "dumbass."
我知道  听见了
I know. I heard.
现在看来  无奈之下
Given this situation, I have no choice
我只能收回我之前对
But to withdraw my previous objections
你和莱纳德关系的反对
To your ill-considered relationship with leonard.
那还真要谢谢你了
Oh, gee, well, thank you for that.
不过我想目前
But I think for now,
莱纳德和我只能做朋友了
Leonard and I are just gonna stay friends.
不行  我不接受你这样的回答
No, that response is unacceptable to me.
谢尔顿  你是个聪明人
Sheldon, you are a smart guy.
-你一定知道  -我"聪明"
You must know... I'm "smart"?
我要是被归类为"聪明"  我的智商测试就要少六十分了
I'd have to lose 60 iq points to be classified as "smart."
你还让我说下去吗
Are you gonna let me talk?
对不起
I'm sorry.
你一定知道如果莱纳德和莱斯利要在一起
You must know that if leonard and leslie want to be together,
你怎么做都阻止不了的
Nothing you can do is gonna stop it.
你又在低估我的智商了  小姐
You continue to underestimate my capabilities, madam.
好了  这么说好了
Okay, let me put it this way.
如果你拿莱纳德当朋友  你要支持他
If you're really leonard's friend, you will support him
不管他和谁在一起
No matter who he wants to be with.
等会
Wait a minute.
为什么老要我支持他
Why am I doing all the giving here?
如果莱纳德拿我当朋友
If leonard's really my friend,
为什么他不支持我
Why doesn't he have to support me
讨厌莱斯利·温克尔
An my hatred of leslie winkle?
因为爱大于恨
Because love trumps hate.
哦  你现在是和事佬了
Oh, now you're just making stuff up.
好了  晚安  谢尔顿
Okay, good night, sheldon.
马里奥  真希望能像控制你一样
Oh, mario, if only I could control everyone
控制所有人
The way I control you.
跳呀  你这小管道工  跳跳跳
Hop, you little plumber, hop, hop, hop.
当你们到自然暂停时
When the two of you reach a natural stopping point,
我想说点事
I'd like to have a word.
你要说的是"尿尿"  去就好了
The word is "pee-pee." just do it.
莱纳德  你是我朋友
Leonard, you're my friend,
朋友就应该支持朋友
And friends support their friends...
显然如此
Apparently.
所以我收回对你想和莱斯利发展 的反对
So I'm withdrawing my objection to your desire to have a relationship with leslie.
谢谢
Thank you.
我会很绅士地
I will graciously
忽略一个事实  她是个又傲慢
Overlook the fact that she is an arrogant,
水平又低的科学家  竟然认为圈量子引力论
Subpar scientist who actually believes loop quantum gravity
比弦理论更好地结合了
Better unites quantum mechanics with generally relativity
量子力学和广义相对论
Than does string theory.
你们好好玩
You kids have fun.
等下
Hang on a second.
圈量子引力论比弦理论更明确地提供了
Loop quantum gravity clearly offers more testable predictions
可验证的假设
Than string theory.
我听着呢  嘲弄我吧
I'm listening. amuse me.
好的  首先  在量子时空观里
Okay, well, for one thing, we expect quantized space-time
细小的不同呈现为
To manifest itself as minute differences
不同光谱的不同速度
In the speed of light for different colors.
胡扯  事物显然是由无数细小闭弦组成的
Balderdash. matter clearly consists of tiny strings.
你就让他这么和我说话
Are you gonna let him talk to me like that?
两种理论都有道理
Okay, well, there is a lot of merit to both theories.
不  不是的  只有圈量子引力论
No, there isn't. only loop quantum gravity
计算出了黑洞的熵
Calculates the entropy of black holes.
谢尔顿  别发出那种声音  很不尊重人
Sheldon, don't make that noise. it's disrespectful.
我倒希望能尊敬
I should hope so.
这是嘲笑的鼻音
It was a snort of derision.
你赞同我的意见  对吧
You agree with me, right?
圈量子引力论是物理学的未来
Loop quantum gravity is the future of physics.
抱歉  莱斯利  我更倾向于空间弦化  而不是圈化
Sorry, leslie, I guess I prefer my space stringy, not loopy.
我很庆幸在我们更进一步之前
I'm glad I found out the truth about you
发现你的真正想法
Before this went any further.
真正想法  什么真正想法
Truth? what truth?
我们讨论的是未验证的假想
We're talking about untested hypotheses.
没什么大不了的
It's no big deal.
没什么  真的吗
It isn't? really?
告诉我  莱纳德  我们怎么告诉孩子们
Tell me, leonard, how will we raise the children?
我  我想等他们大了
I... I guess we wait until they're old enough
让他们自己选择自己相信的理论
And let them choose their own theory.
不能让他们自己选  莱纳德  他们是孩子
We can't let them choose, leonard. they're children!
等会  你去哪
Wait. where are you going?
很抱歉
I'm sorry.
我可以接受我们的孩子
I could have accepted our kids being
在基因上不能吃冰激凌
Genetically unable to eat ice cream
或者对走台也没有坏印象
Or ever get a good view of a parade.
但这个
But this?
这是原则问题
This is a deal breaker.
-看好的一面吧  -好的一面是什么
-Look on the bright side. -What's the bright side?
还有九个月就到动漫盛会了
Only nine more months to comic-con.
太好了
Oh, yeah.
船长  我捕获到异常信号
Captain, I'm getting an unusual reading.
哦  还不错
Yeah, that's great.
你们想要玉米肠吗
You guys want a corn dog?
好的
Yeah.
时代混乱
That's a temporal anomaly.
玉米肠直到
Corn dog's didn't come into existence
二十世纪上半叶才出现
Till the first half of the 20th century.